// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options, and answers
let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which of the following elements of electrical engineering cannot be analyzed using Ohmâ€™s law?",
    answer: "c) Transistors",
    options: [
      "a) Capacitors",
      "b) Inductors",
      "c) Transistors",
      "d) Resistance"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is constant for a charged spherical shell according to basic electrical energy?",
    answer: "b) Electrical potential inside the spherical shell",
    options: [
      "a) Electrical potential outside the spherical shell",
      "b) Electrical potential inside the spherical shell",
      "c) Electrical field outside the spherical shell",
      "d) Electrical field inside the spherical shell"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Where does electro-static shielding occur in a charged spherical shell?",
    answer: "d) Electrical field inside the spherical shell",
    options: [
      "a) When electrical potential outside spherical shell is zero",
      "b) When electrical potential inside the spherical shell is zero",
      "c) When electrical field outside the spherical shell",
      "d) Electrical field inside the spherical shell",
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which of the following is a correct representation of peak value in an AC Circuit?",
    answer: "d) RMS value*Peak factor",
    options: [
      "a) RMS value/Peak factor",
      "b) RMS value*Form factor",
      "c) RMS value/Form factor",
      "d) RMS value*Peak factor"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Which of the following according to fundaments of electrical energy is correct about alternating current?",
    answer: "a) Frequency is zero",
    options: [
      "a) Frequency is zero",
      "b) Magnitude changes with time",
      "c) Can be transported to larger distances with less loss in power",
      "d) Flows in both directions"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 6,
    question: "How many cycles will an AC signal make in 2 seconds if its frequency is 100 Hz?",
    answer: "d) 200",
    options: [
      "a) 50",
      "b) 100",
      "c) 150",
      "d) 200"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 7,
    question: "What will be the direction of the drift velocity of electrons change with respect to the electric field?",
    answer: "b) opposite to that of electric field",
    options: [
      "a) same as that of electric field",
      "b) opposite to that of electric field",
      "c) perpendicular to that of the electric field in a positive direction",
      "d) perpendicular to that of the electric field in a negative direction"
    ]
  }
  ,
    {
    numb: 8,
    question: "What kind of quantity is an Electric potential?",
    answer: "c) Scalar quantity",
    options: [
      "a) Vector quantity",
      "b) Tensor quantity",
      "c) Scalar quantity",
      "d) Dimensionless quantity"
    ]
  }
  ,
    {
    numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is correct about the power consumed by R1 and R2 connected in series if the value of R1 is greater than R2?",
    answer: "a) R1 will consume more power",
    options: [
      "a) R1 will consume more power",
      "b) R2 will consume more power",
      "c) R1 and R2 will consume the same power",
      "d) The relationship between the power consumed cannot be established"
    ]
  }
  ,
    {
    numb: 10,
    question: "What is zero for a charged spherical shell?",
    answer: "d) Electrical field inside the spherical shell",
    options: [
      "a) Electrical potential outside the spherical shell",
      "b) Electrical potential inside the spherical shell",
      "c) Electrical field outside the spherical shell",
      "d) Electrical field inside the spherical shell"
    ]
  }
  

];